Edwin Way Teale Papers 1981.0009
Archives and Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
Edwin Way Teale Papers
undated, 1799-1995
Archives and Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
1981.0009
238 Linear Feet
Edwin Way Teale, Connecticut-based naturalist, was the author of thirty-two books. His papers include field notes and drafts for each of his books, early childhood writings, professional writings for magazines, newspapers and book reviews, correspondence- both personal and professional, personal and family documents, scrapbooks, and memorabilia, as well as his photographs (prints, negatives, and transparencies) and his personal library. There is also one box of original John Burroughs material Teale collected over the years.
Access
Prior permission to view still-camera film negatives in boxes 263-270 is required due to fragility.
Acquisition Information
Two large donations were made by the author, Edwin Way Teale, and then by Nellie Teale after her husband's death.
Arrangement
There are thirteen Series within the Edwin Way Teale Papers.
Series I: Writings (undated, 1799-1991) contains EWT's writings and includes his book related material, early writings, published and unpublished articles or essays, and the manuscripts for his speeches.
Series II: Journals and Diaries (undated, 1799-1991) contains Edwin's journals and diaries ranging from the his early childhood to his death in 1980. Nellie's journals and diaries are also included in this series.
Series III: Correspondence (undated, 1907-1991) is comprised of both Nellie's and Edwin's correspondence up to his death in October of 1980, and is separated into appropriate sub-series.
Series IV: Print Material (undated, 1885-1995) includes printed material; magazines and newspapers that EWT published articles in and those he collected for his personal library.
Series V: Clubs and Societies (undated, 1930-1991) relates solely to Clubs and Societies of which he was involved in and includes related correspondence and publications.
Series VI: Family Papers (undated, 1850-1991) contains family material from his mother, son and grandparents, and also includes Nellie's material (such as birding notes) after October of 1980.
Series VII: Scrapbooks (undated, 1914-1979) is devoted to scrapbooks.
Series VIII: Artifacts and Samples (undated, 1950-1978) contains associated artifacts.
Series IX: Camera Equipment and Media (undated, 1958-1989) contains cameras, camera accessories, LP record albums, cassette tapes, and films. The cameras and accessories were used by Teale to take the negatives and transparencies contained in Series XIII: Photographs. The LP record albums and cassettes contain interviews with Teale as well as a reading from his book Dune Boy. The LP record albums are separated from the Teale Papers but can be located with a separate LP call number. The films are primarily 16mm color and are mostly documenting insects as well as Teale working in his Insect Garden. Some of the films are warped and will require careful handling to view. The films are separated from the Teale Papers but can be located with a separate mp number.
Series X: Memorabilia (undated, 1801-1990s) includes associated memorabilia.
Series XI: Other Author's Manuscript Material Given to EWT & NDT (undated, 1951-1991) contains other author's manuscript material that was given to Nellie or Edwin.
Series XII: John Burroughs Material (undated, 1901-1946) collected by Edwin Way Teale and includes letters, original writings and manuscripts.
Series XIII: Photographs (undated, 1860s-1990s) includes black-and-white negatives on glass and film, color transparencies, and black-and-white prints. Each subseries is uniquely arranged to best house the materials and assist researchers. >Subseries A: Negatives are arranged by size (3" x 4", 120mm) and chronology. Subseries B: Transparencies are arranged by format (transparency, lantern slides, slides), chronology, and subject. Subseries C: Prints are arranged by subject. Subseries D: Publication Related Materials are arranged by format (negatives, prints), size (3" x 4", 120mm, 8" x 10"), and publication title. Subseries E: Personal Photographs are arranged by subject and chronology. Subseries F: John Burroughs Related Material is arranged by format (negative, prints).
Biography
Edwin "Way" Teale (christened Edwin Albert Teale) was born on 2 June 1899 in Joliet, Illinois. His father, Oliver Cromwell Teale, was British and had emigrated from England in 1884. After working in New York and then Illinois as a railroad mechanic, he met his future wife, Clara Louise Way at a party hosted by her parents. The future Mrs. Oliver Teale had grown up on "Lone Oak" farm, which Edwin fondly wrote about in his book Dune Boy. Edwin's early years were kept busy with church, school, and more "school" at home, his mother having been a teacher. Although he always felt connected with nature, it was only during the summers, visiting his grandparents at Lone Oak farm, that he was able to roam free. Edwin kept a journal from very early on, documenting the natural world and things he found interesting.
In 1918, Edwin Way Teale enlisted in the Student Army Training Corps, but was discharged only two months later. He then transferred to Earlham College, where his uncle, David Edwards, was President. It was at Earlham where he met Nellie Imogene Donovan. She was instrumental in his life as a wife, friend, assistant and editor. Edwin's major in college was English, and he was active in many clubs and sports teams including the Football Team, Oratory Club and Debating Team.
After graduating from Earlham in 1922, Edwin took a job as head of the department of public speaking and debate at Friend's University in Wichita, Kansas. Nellie graduated in the spring of 1923 and they were married on 1 August. The Teales stayed for one more year at Friend's, Edwin continued teaching while Nellie became the athletic director.
The Teales then journeyed to New York, where Edwin entered Columbia University. While obtaining his Masters degree and working on his thesis paper entitled Jeffries Criticism of Wordsworth and Scott he submitted his editorials to Dr. Crane, a noted editorial writer. During this time the Teales had their only child, David. After graduating, Teale had hopes of getting a job on the editorial staff of Columbia Dispatch, but after several months of waiting for the official offer and a dwindling bank account, Edwin was forced to try his luck in New York. It was here where he began his decade long career at Popular Science. Edwin wrote on average, four articles an issue, some ghost-written, anonymous or written using pen names. In 1942, after having success with freelance articles, and his first few books (A Book About Gliders, The Golden Throng), he resigned to work full time for himself.
The following years were filled with happiness and great sadness. Although Edwin's career as a writer, photographer and public speaker prospered, David joined the army at 18. While on a reconnaissance mission in Germany, David was killed when a bomb sunk the small boat he was on. David and several others drowned. For almost a year, David's status was Missing in Action. After months of inquiries they finally discovered most of what happened and were given the official letter by the government. As Edwin stated, the only thing that kept them from despair was their love of nature.
In 1959, Edwin and Nellie decided to move from their home in Baldwin, New York, to a more rural area. After touring the area in a hot-air balloon they decided to purchase a seventy-nine acre property in Hampton, Connecticut they named "Trail Wood". He documented their quest for the perfect home in his book entitled A Naturalist Buys an Old Farm. Frequently the Teales welcomed visitors: fans, hikers and naturalists wishing a tour, or just to explore the property.
Edwin and Nellie were members of such organizations and societies as the Thoreau Society, the Explorer's Club, the John Burroughs Memorial Association and the New York Entomological Society. They were good friends with many other naturalists and kept extensive correspondence, with relatives, friends, fans, and other influential people including Rachel Carson, Roger Tory Peterson, William T. Davis, andJulian Burroughs. His 32 books have been published in many languages, as well as in Braille. He won the Pulitzer prize in 1966, and received the Burroughs Medal in 1943 for his book, Near Horizons, among other awards and honors. His fans continued to send Edwin and Nellie letters even after his death in October 1980. Edwin and Nellie chose to donate their materials to the University of Connecticut Library and preserved Trail Wood by donating it to the Connecticut Audubon Society. It is now known as the Edwin Way Teale Memorial Sanctuary and is seasonally open for tours.
Scope and Content Note
Teale's papers include field notes and drafts for each of his books, early childhood writings, professional writings for magazines, newspapers and book reviews, correspondence- both personal and professional, personal and family documents, scrapbooks, and memorabilia, as well as his photographs (prints, negatives, and transparencies) and his personal library. There is also one box of original John Burroughs material Teale collected over the years.
Insect Friends.; The Book of Gliders.; The Junior Book of Insects.; Personal papers; The Golden Throng.; Near Horizons.; Grassroot Jungles.; The Junior Book of Photography.; Byways to Adventure.; Naturalists; A Conscious Stillness.; American Seasons.; Photographs of American Nature.; Wandering Through Winter.; The Thoughts of Thoreau.; Manuscripts (document genre); The Lost Dog.; Adventures in Nature; Journey Into Summer.; Autumn Across America.; Audubon's Wildlife.; The Strange Lives of Familiar Insects.; A Naturalist Buys An Old Farm.; Springtime in Britain.; A Walk Through the Year; The Lost Woods.; Dune Boy.; The Insect World of J. Henri Fabre.; Days Without Time.; The Wilderness World of John Muir.; Photographers; Green Treasury.; Circle of the Seasons.; North With the Spring.; Memorabilia; Equipment and supplies; Authors; Correspondence; Green Mansions.; Walden Woods (Mass.); Publications (documents); Photographs; Teale, Edwin Way, 1899-1980; Zwinger, Ann
- Series I: Writings, undated, 1799-1991
  - Subseries A: Books, undated, 1871-1991
    - EWT's Summary of his Reviewed Books, undated (Box 1:, Folder 1)
    - Book Title Ideas- saved for scrapbook, undated (Box 1:, Folder 2)
    - The Book of Gliders, (1930)
      - Notes, undated (Box 1:, Folder 3)
      - Notes, undated (Box 1:, Folder 4)
      - Clippings, Periodicals, 1928-1931 (Box 1:, Folder 5)
      - Newspaper Clippings, undated, 1922-1931 (Box 1:, Folder 6)
      - Pamphlets, undated (Box 1:, Folder 7)
      - "Gliding", undated (Box 1:, Folder 8)
      - "Gliders", undated (Box 1:, Folder 9)
      - "Gyroplanes", undated (Box 1:, Folder 10)
      - Drawings, undated (Box 1:, Folder 11)
      - Gymnich, Alfried "Structural Details of German Gliders" Technical Memorandum # 439, 1927 November (Box 1:, Folder 12)
      - Lippisch, A. "Technical Report of the 1928 Rhon Soaring Flight Contest", Technical Memorandum 514, 1929 May (Box 1:, Folder 13)
      - Postcard Picture, undated (Box 1:, Folder 14)
      - Diagrams, undated (Box 1:, Folder 15)
      - Indexes and Outlines, undated (Box 1:, Folder 16)
      - Introduction, Handwritten by W.H. Bowlus, undated (Box 1:, Folder 17)
      - Preface, undated (Box 1:, Folder 18)
      - Chapter V, "Gottlob Espenlaub Story", undated (Box 1:, Folder 19)
      - Chapter VI, "Max Kegal, Arthur Martens Stories", undated (Box 1:, Folder 20)
      - Chapter XIII, Draft, undated (Box 1:, Folder 21)
      - Notes, undated (Box 1:, Folder 22)
      - Photographs With Captions, undated (Box 1:, Folder 23)
      - Photograph Proofs, undated (Box 1:, Folder 24)
      - Reviews and Clippings, 1930-1931 (Box 1:, Folder 25)
    - Grassroot Jungles, (1937)
      - Write-up by Teale for Time Magazine, 1937 October (Box 1:, Folder 26)
      - Book Reviews and Clippings, 1937-1938 (Box 1:, Folder 27)
      - Book Reviews and Clippings, 1937-1938 (Box 1:, Folder 28)
      - Marketing Brochure, 1937 (Box 1:, Folder 29)
      - Signature Sheets, 1937 (Box 1:, Folder 30-31)
      - Research Material, undated (Box 1:, Folder 32)
      - Notes, undated (Box 1:, Folder 33-35)
      - Content Listing, undated (Box 1:, Folder 36)
      - Chapter I, "Exploring at Home", Drafts, undated (Box 1:, Folder 37)
      - Chapter II, "Insect ABC's", undated (Box 1:, Folder 38)
      - Chapter III, "Winged Bullets—Dragonflies", Drafts, undated (Box 1:, Folder 39)
      - Chapter IV, "Mystery of the Monarch", Drafts, undated (Box 1:, Folder 40)
      - Chapter V, "A Garden Dinosaur", Drafts, undated (Box 1:, Folder 41)
      - Chapter VI, "Living Pastures—The Aphids", Drafts, undated (Box 1:, Folder 42)
      - Chapter VII, "The Robber Fly", Drafts, undated (Box 1:, Folder 43)
      - Chapter VIII, "Polyphemus the Giant", undated (Box 1:, Folder 44)
      - Chapter IX, "Two Legs, Too Many-- The Spiders", Drafts, undated (Box 1:, Folder 45)
      - Chapter X, "The Strange Life of the Bumble Bee", Drafts, undated (Box 1:, Folder 46)
      - Chapter XI, "Insect Lilliput", Drafts, undated (Box 1:, Folder 47)
      - Chapter XII, "Six-Legged Rip Van Winkle", Drafts, undated (Box 1:, Folder 48)
      - Chapter XIII, "Beauty and the Beast", Drafts, undated (Box 1:, Folder 49)
      - Chapter XIV, "The Old Man of the Garden", Draft, undated (Box 1:, Folder 50)
      - Chapter XV, "Wisdom of the Wasp", Draft, undated (Box 1:, Folder 51)
      - Chapter XVI, "Ant Lore", Draft, undated (Box 1:, Folder 52)
      - Chapter XVII, "The First Fiddler", Draft, undated (Box 1:, Folder 53)
      - Chapter XVIII, "Flying Rainbows", Drafts, undated (Box 1:, Folder 54)
      - Chapter XIX, "The Homeless Ladybug", Draft, undated (Box 1:, Folder 55)
      - Chapter XX, "Night Singers", Draft, undated (Box 1:, Folder 56)
      - Chapter XXI, "How to Photograph Insects", Draft, undated (Box 1:, Folder 57)
      - Chapter XXII, "Summer's End", Draft, undated (Box 1:, Folder 58)
      - Picture Captions, undated (Box 1:, Folder 59)
      - Incomplete Chapters, undated (Box 1:, Folder 60)
      - Advertisement, undated (Box 1:, Folder 61)
      - Revised Edition, Preface Drafts, undated (Box 1:, Folder 62)
      - Book Jackets, undated; (2) (Box 1:, Folder 63)
    - Boys Book of Photography, (1939)
      - Notes, undated (Box 1:, Folder 64)
      - Clippings—Periodicals, undated, 1934 (Box 1:, Folder 65)
      - Synopsis, Contents, Outline, Dedication, undated (Box 1:, Folder 66)
      - Foreword—Drafts, Edited, 1939 July - September (Box 1:, Folder 67)
      - Chapter XIV, "Table Top Photography", Draft, Handwritten, undated (Box 1:, Folder 68)
      - Chapter XIX, "Candid Camera Pictures", Draft, Handwritten, undated (Box 1:, Folder 69)
      - Manuscript Pages, Edited, undated (Box 1:, Folder 70)
      - Book Jacket, undated (Box 1:, Folder 71)
      - Advertisement, 1941 (Box 1:, Folder 72)
    - The Boys Book of Insects, (1939) (Box not specified)
      - Notes, undated (Box 2:, Folder 73)
      - Schedules, 1938 May - September (Box 2:, Folder 74)
      - Chapter I, "The Insect World", Draft, Edited, undated (Box 2:, Folder 75)
      - Manuscript Pages, Miscellaneous, undated (Box 2:, Folder 76)
      - Back Flap Quiz Questions, undated (Box 2:, Folder 77)
      - Research, Notes, Draft of Changes, Correspondence, 1952 March 11 (Box 2:, Folder 78)
      - Reviews of Book, 1939 (Box 2:, Folder 79)
    - The Junior Book of Insects (2nd Revision)
      - Notes, Drafts of Revisions, 1972 (Box 2:, Folder 80)
      - Chapter XXII, "Insect Warfare", 1973 (Box 2:, Folder 81)
      - Line Corrections, 1973 (Box 2:, Folder 82)
      - Addition and Replacement Pages, 1973 (Box 2:, Folder 83)
      - Revised Manuscript, 1972 (Box 2:, Folder 84)
      - Correspondence, 1972 (Box 2:, Folder 85)
    - The Golden Throng, (1940)
      - Notes, undated (Box 2:, Folder 86)
      - Chapter Outline, undated (Box 2:, Folder 87)
      - Table of Contents, undated (Box 2:, Folder 88)
      - Chapter I, Early Drafts, undated (Box 2:, Folder 89)
      - Chapter I, "Rise of an Insect City", 1939 December 20 - 21 (Box 2:, Folder 90)
      - Chapter I, "Rise of an Insect City", 1939 December 29 - 31 (Box 2:, Folder 91)
      - Chapter I, "Rise of an Insect City" (Eternal Ways), 1940 January 4 (Box 2:, Folder 92)
      - Chapter I, "Eternal Ways", undated (Box 2:, Folder 93)
      - Chapter II, "Rise of the Insect City", undated (Box 2:, Folder 94)
      - Chapter III, "Springtide", undated (Box 2:, Folder 95)
      - Chapter IV, "Bee Is World", Incomplete, undated (Box 2:, Folder 96)
      - Chapter XIV, "Books and Bees", undated (Box 2:, Folder 97)
      - Reviews and Clippings, 1940-1942 (Box 2:, Folder 97B-98)
      - Signature Pages, undated (Box 2:, Folder 99)
      - Marketing Pamphlets (3), undated (Box 2:, Folder 100)
      - Signature Pages, undated (Box 2:, Folder 101)
      - Revision: Notes, Revised Chapters of Manuscript, Correspondence, 1961 (Box 2:, Folder 102)
    - Byways to Adventure, (1942)
      - Notes, undated (Box 2:, Folder 103)
      - Notes—Mammals, undated (Box 2:, Folder 104)
      - Schedules, 1941-1942 (Box 2:, Folder 105)
      - Chapter I, "Byways to Adventure", undated (Box 2:, Folder 106)
      - Chapter II, "Bird Watching", undated (Box 2:, Folder 107)
      - Chapter III, "The Pageant of Weather", undated (Box 2:, Folder 108)
      - Chapter IV, "Exploring the Sky", undated (Box 2:, Folder 109)
      - Chapter V, "Journeys to Lilliput", undated (Box 2:, Folder 110)
      - Chapter VI, "Deserted Homes", undated (Box 2:, Folder 111)
      - Chapter VII, "Reptile Lore", undated (Box 2:, Folder 112)
      - Chapter VIII, "The World of the Trees", undated (Box 2:, Folder 113)
      - Chapter IX, "Green Realm—the Plants", undated (Box 2:, Folder 114)
      - Chapter X, "Wonderland of the Microscope", undated (Box 2:, Folder 115)
      - Chapter XI, "Rock Hobbies", undated (Box 2:, Folder 116)
      - Chapter XII, "The Four-Footed", undated (Box 2:, Folder 117)
      - Chapter XIII, "Fossil Hunting", undated (Box 2:, Folder 118)
      - Chapter XIV, "The Underwater World", undated (Box 2:, Folder 119)
      - Chapter XVI, "Nature in Focus", undated (Box 2:, Folder 120)
      - Chapter XVII, "The Outdoors Brought Indoors—Museums", undated (Box 2:, Folder 121)
      - Book Jacket, undated (Box 2:, Folder 122)
      - Reviews and Clippings, 1942 (Box 2:, Folder 123)
    - Near Horizons, (1942)
      - Schedules, "Things To Do", 1942? (Box 2:, Folder 124)
      - "Gardening Made Easy"—Booklet, 1871 (Box 2:, Folder 125)
      - Notes, 1942 (Box 2:, Folder 126-129)
      - Notes—Ants, undated (Box 2:, Folder 130)
      - Notes—Aphids, undated (Box 2:, Folder 131)
      - Notes—Bees, undated (Box 2:, Folder 132)
      - Notes—Butterflies, undated (Box 2:, Folder 133)
      - Notes—Cicadas, undated (Box 2:, Folder 134)
      - Notes—Crickets, Katydids, Grasshoppers, undated (Box 2:, Folder 135)
      - Notes—Flies, undated (Box 2:, Folder 136)
      - Notes—Moths, undated (Box 2:, Folder 137)
      - Notes—Spiders, undated (Box 2:, Folder 138)
      - Notes—Foreword, undated (Box 2:, Folder 139)
      - Chapter I, "The Story of an Insect Garden", Notes, undated (Box 2:, Folder 140)
      - Chapter I, "The Story of an Insect Garden", Draft, undated (Box 2:, Folder 141)
      - Chapter II, "Mysterious Neighbors", Notes, undated (Box 2:, Folder 142)
      - Chapter II, "Mysterious Neighbors", Drafts, undated (Box 2:, Folder 143)
      - Chapter III, "House of Bubbles", Notes, undated (Box 2:, Folder 144)
      - Chapter III, "House of Bubbles", Drafts, undated (Box 2:, Folder 145)
      - Chapter IV, "Butterfly Battles", Drafts, undated (Box 2:, Folder 146)
      - Chapter V, "An Adventure in Viewpoints", Drafts, undated (Box 2:, Folder 147)
      - Chapter VI, "The Insect's Horizon", Drafts, undated (Box 2:, Folder 148)
      - Chapter VII, "Historian of the Little World", Drafts, undated (Box 3:, Folder 149)
      - Chapter VIII, "Night in the Garden", Drafts, undated (Box 3:, Folder 150)
      - Chapter X, "Ghost Bugs", Notes, undated (Box 3:, Folder 151)
      - Chapter XII, "Birds in an Insect Garden", Notes, undated (Box 3:, Folder 152)
      - Chapter XIV, "Antennae Tales", Notes, undated (Box 3:, Folder 153)
      - Chapter XV, "The Chlorophyll Mountains", Notes, undated (Box 3:, Folder 154)
      - Chapter XVIII, "The Story of a Million Seconds", Notes, undated (Box 3:, Folder 155)
      - Chapter XIX, "One Square Inch of Earth", Notes, undated (Box 3:, Folder 156)
      - Chapter XX, "Insect Hollywood", Notes, undated (Box 3:, Folder 157)
      - Chapter XXI, "If I Were A Wasp", Notes, undated (Box 3:, Folder 158)
      - Chapter XXII, "Insect Mystery Stories", Notes, undated (Box 3:, Folder 159)
      - Chapter XXIII, "War on a Rosebush", Notes, undated (Box 3:, Folder 160)
      - Chapter XXV, "Moles Way", Notes, undated (Box 3:, Folder 161)
      - Chapter XXVI, "Life on the Shallow Water", Notes, undated (Box 3:, Folder 162)
      - Chapter XXVIII, "Dinah Was a Mantis", Notes, undated (Box 3:, Folder 163)
      - Chapter XXIX, "Creatures of the Sun", Notes, undated (Box 3:, Folder 164)
      - Title Pages, Dedication, List of Illustrations, undated (Box 3:, Folder 165)
      - Table of Contents—Drafts, undated (Box 3:, Folder 166)
      - Foreword—Drafts, undated (Box 3:, Folder 167)
      - Chapter IX, "Knothole Cavern", Drafts, undated (Box 3:, Folder 168)
      - Chapter X, "Ghost Bugs", Drafts, undated (Box 3:, Folder 169)
      - Chapter XI, "The Hills of Lilliput", Drafts, undated (Box 3:, Folder 170)
      - Chapter XII, "Birds in an Insect Garden", Drafts, undated (Box 3:, Folder 171)
      - Chapter XIII, "Cicada Man", Drafts, undated (Box 3:, Folder 172)
      - Chapter XIV, "Antennae Tales", undated (Box 3:, Folder 173)
      - Chapter XV, "The Chlorophyll Mountains", Drafts, undated (Box 3:, Folder 174)
      - Chapter XVI, "And Things That Go Bump In the Night", Drafts, undated (Box 3:, Folder 175)
      - Chapter XVII, "Painted Bumblebees", Drafts, undated (Box 3:, Folder 176)
      - Chapter XVIII, "The Story of a Million Seconds", Drafts, undated (Box 3:, Folder 177)
      - Chapter XIX, "One Square Inch of Earth", undated (Box 3:, Folder 178)
      - Chapter XX, "Insect Hollywood", Drafts, undated (Box 3:, Folder 179)
      - Chapter XXI, "If I Were a Wasp", Drafts, undated (Box 3:, Folder 18)
      - Chapter XXII, "Insect Mystery Stories", Drafts, undated (Box 3:, Folder 181)
      - Chapter XXIII, "War on a Rosebush", Drafts, undated (Box 3:, Folder 182)
      - Chapter XXIV, "The Dance of the Craneflies", Drafts, undated (Box 3:, Folder 183)
      - Chapter XXV, "Mole's Way", Drafts, undated (Box 3:, Folder 184)
      - Chapter XXVI, "Life on the Shallow Water", Drafts, undated (Box 3:, Folder 185)
      - Chapter XXVII, "Fiddler's Progress", Drafts, undated (Box 3:, Folder 186)
      - Chapter XXVIII, "Dinah Was a Mantis", Drafts, undated (Box 3:, Folder 187)
      - Chapter XXIX, "Creatures of the Sun", Drafts, undated (Box 3:, Folder 188)
      - Chapter XXX, "Days of the Lost Sunshine", Drafts, undated (Box 3:, Folder 189)
      - Entomological Epilogue, Draft, undated (Box 3:, Folder 190)
      - Index—Draft, undated (Box 3:, Folder 191)
      - Chapters I—V, Manuscript, Edited, 1942 August (Box 3:, Folder 192)
      - Chapters VI—X, Manuscript, Edited, 1942 August (Box 3:, Folder 193)
      - Chapters XI—XV, Manuscript, Edited, 1942 August (Box 3:, Folder 194)